Preliminary Guide to the Brewster Family Papers 1878-1979
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Preliminary Guide to the Brewster Family Papers
1878-1979
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
MSSM.056
Brewster, Carl Milton, 1881-1961
27 Boxes
The material in this collection relates to Carl Milton Brewster and Alfhild Nordby Brewster.
Carl Milton Brewster (1881-1961) was Professor of Organic Chemistry at Washington State University from 1912 to 1950. He was born in Chagrin Falls, Ohio, the son of Milton Brewster and Mary (Lambert) Brewster. He received his A.B. degree from Oberlin College in 1903, and then taught high school science for two years at Two Harbors, Minnesota. He then pursued graduate study in organic chemistry, receiving his A.M. degree from Harvard University in 1906. He was Francis Parkman Fellow at Harvard from 1908 to 1909. Brewster continued his studies at Heidelberg University prior to becoming professor of chemistry at Mount Union College (1910-1912). After his marriage to Alfhild Nordby in 1912, he joined the faculty of the State College of Washington. (From the guide to the Carl Milton Brewster Papers, Cage 44)
Carl Milton Brewster and Alfhild Nordby Brewster had three children: Carl (1913-1987), Josephine (1914-2001), and Milton (1917-2005).
The material in this collection relates to Carl Milton Brewster and Alfhild Nordby Brewster, and their three children. Most are personal papers, along with some material related to C.M. Brewster's research and teaching at Washington State College.
MS.2005.16: Carl Milton Brewster papers, with some Brewster family papers. The bulk of the collection is scrapbooks, most created by Carl Milton Brewster, on various topics, and notebooks related to his research and teaching.
MS.2006.06: Papers of the Carl Milton Brewster family, mainly Carl MIlton Brewster and his wife, Alfhild Nordby Brewster.
MS.2014.30: This collection of Brewster family papers includes photographs (mainly family photos, including many from their Pullman homes at 900 Campus and 1721 Maple), a small amount of correspondence, and ephemera. Some collectible stamps from C.M. Brewster's stamp collection are also present, including some from Nazi Germany.
This is an unprocessed collection. Arrangement reflects a pre-existing order from the records’ creators or previous custodians.
This collection is open and available for research use.
Members of the Brewster family donated this collection to the Washington State University Libraries in multiple installments in 2005 and 2006 (MS.2005.16, MS.2006.06, MS.2014.30).
Books received with this collection have been cataloged separately.
Carl Milton Brewster Papers, 1902-1958 (Cage 44)
Carl Milton Brewster Autograph Collection, 1760-1900 (Cage 391)
Cosmopolitan Club, Washington State University, Papers, 1925-1946 (Cage 703)
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Brewster, Carl Milton, 1881-1961 -- Records and correspondence.; Brewster, Alfhild Nordby -- Records and correspondence.
Brewster Family
Pullman (Wash.) -- History -- Sources.
Washington State University -- Faculty -- Archives.
Washington (State)
- MS.2005.16: Carl Milton Brewster Papers, 1878-circa 1960
  - Carl Milton Brewster biographical information; "Indians" files; WSU and miscellaneous files; scrapbooks. (Box 1)
  - Scrapbooks. (Box 2-4)
  - Notebooks related to C.M. Brewster's research and teaching. (Box 5)
  - Notebooks (continued); Brewster thesis files; "Booksellers" file. (Box 6)
  - Photographs, including some labeled as "Indians"; family photographs; Josephine Brewster correspondence; audio recordings "First Aid French for American Soldiers," 1917 (disks and phrasebooks). (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous C.M. Brewster papers; miscellaneous loose items; research and teaching files; scrapbook (Josephine). (Box 8)
  - Artifact: club [Native American origin?]; broadside for invitational basketball tournament; photographs [Milton?]; academy membership certificate, C.M. Brewster. (Box 9)
- MS.2006.06: Brewster family papers, 1900-1979
  - Carl Milton Brewster correspondence (unsorted). (Box 1)
  - Alfhild Nordby Brewster correspondence (partly sorted). (Box 2-6)
  - Brewster family correspondence (partly sorted). (Box 6-7)
  - Brewster family correspondence (partly sorted)., circa 1930s (Box 8)
  - Brewster family correspondence (partly sorted)., circa 1940s (Box 9)
  - Brewster family correspondence (partly sorted)., circa 1940s-1950s (Box 10)
  - Brewster family correspondence (partly sorted)., circa 1950s (Box 11-12)
  - Brewster family correspondence (partly sorted)., circa 1960s-1970s (Box 13)
  - Family: travel and miscellaneous. (Box 14)
  - Carl Milton Brewster. (Box 15)
  - Family: diaries, planners, miscellaneous. (Box 16)
  - Photographs. (Box 17)
- MS.2014.30: Brewster Family Papers, circa 1910s-1960
  - Papers (Box 1)
  - Photographs (Box 2)